Finding Aid for Henry B. Baker papers, 1871-1900
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Henry B. Baker papers 1871-1900
Baker, Henry B. (Henry Brooks), 1837-1920.
1 linear foot.
8512 Aa 2
Founder and first secretary of the Michigan State Board of Health; papers of Baker and his son Howard B. Baker.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dr. Burton Baker (Donor no. 6965 ) and came to the library in 1983.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Henry B. Baker was a founder and first secretary of the Michigan State Board of Health
The Baker collection includes correspondence, reports, and other manuscripts relating to professional activities and his interest in public health matters. There are also some papers of his son Howard B. Baker, notably notebooks and papers while he was a student at Michigan Agricultural College.
Subjects:
Michigan. State Board of Health.; State Agricultural College (Mich.); University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery.; Public health--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Aged persons.; Baker, Henry B. (Henry Brooks), 1837-1920.; Mexico.; Quarantines.
Contributors:
Baker, Howard Bigelow.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Henry B. Baker Papers
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1875-1900 (Box 1)
  - Resolutions, reports and related re State Board of Health activities, 1878-1900 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts and notes (fragments) (Box 1)
  - Suffrage resolution, 1874 (Box 1)
  - Paper, 1892 describing trip through Mexico (Box 1)
  - Addresses, 1891 and 1899 (Box 1)
  - Articles and clippings about Henry B. Baker (Box 1)
  - Reprints of articles, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Howard B. Baker Papers
  - Student notebooks, 1891-1892 of Howard B. Baker (Box 1)
  - Student addresses and papers of Howard B. Baker (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Portraits of Baker and others; also collected commercial photographs of Mexico, old people, and a steam disinfecting plant (Box 1)